{
    "id":"Unit 0",
    "description":"Foundation Institute Elementary Level Unit 0",
    "exercises":{"0":
		 {
		     "question_prompt":"Write the plural form of these nouns.",
		     "example":
		     {
			 "question":"One chair - Two _______.",
			 "answer":"chairs"
		     },
		     "questions":
		     [
			 {"q":"One car - Two ________",
			  "a":"cars"},
			 {"q":"One table - Two _______",
			  "a":"tables"},
			 {"q":"One man - Two _______",
			  "a":"men"},
			 {"q":"One woman - Two ________",
			  "a":"women"},
			 {"q":"One foot - Two ________",
			  "a":"feet"},
			 {"q":"One class - Two ________",
			  "a":"classes"},
			 {"q":"One person - Two ________",
			  "a":"people"},
			 {"q":"One watch - Two _______",
			  "a":"watches"},
			 {"q":"One box - Two ________",
			  "a":"boxes"},
			 {"q":"One city - Two ________",
			  "a":"cities"},
			 {"q":"One child - Two ________",
			  "a":"children"},
			 {"q":"One knife - Two ________",
			  "a":"knives"},
			 {"q":"One potato - Two ________",
			  "a":"potatoes"},
			 {"q":"One tomato - Two ________",
			  "a":"tomatoes"},
			 {"q":"One fish - Two _________",
			  "a":"fish/fishes"},
			 {"q":"One sheep - Two _________",
			  "a":"sheep"},
			 {"q":"One phone - Two _________",
			  "a":"phones"},
			 {"q":"One cup - Two _________",
			  "a":"cups"},
			 {"q":"One book - Two ________",
			  "a":"books"},
			 {"q":"One country - Two ________",
			  "a":"countries"},
			 {"q":"One world - Two ________",
			  "a":"worlds"}
		     ],
		     "help":"For most nouns you can make the plural form by adding 's' to the word.<br> e.g. car - cars.<br> For nouns ending in 'ss', 'x','ch' or 'sh' you make the plural form by adding 'es'.<br> e.g.<br>'fox - foxes'<br>For nouns ending in a consonant + 'y' you can make the plural form by removing the 'y' and adding 'ies'.<br>e.g.<br>penny - pennies<br>Some nouns are irregular and you need to learn them individually.<br>e.g. man - men<br>",
		     "helpurls":["http://www.edufind.com/english-grammar/plural-nouns/"]

		 },
		 
		 "1":    
		 {
		     "question_prompt":"Use the correct form of the verb 'be'.",
		     "example":
		     {
			 "question":"She _______ a student.",
			 "answer":"is"
		     },
		     "questions":
		     [

			 {
			     "q":"He ________ a doctor.",
			     "a":"is"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"She ________ happy.",
			     "a":"is"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"They __________ my friends.",
			     "a":"are"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"It __________ hot today.",
			     "a":"is"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"You __________ beautiful.",
			     "a":"are"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"My friends ________ very funny.",
			     "a":"are"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"My brother's car ________ blue.",
			     "a":"is"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"Your mother _________ very kind.",
			     "a":"is"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"The people in the room _________ good students.",
			     "a":"are"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"There ________ lots of books on the shelf.",
			     "a":"are"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"I ________ a superstar.",
			     "a":"am"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"My friends and I _________ good at English.",
			     "a":"are"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"Your sister, unlike her friends, _________ very hard working.",
			     "a":"is"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"The boys studying French __________ having lunch.",
			     "a":"are"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"There ________ some water in the glass.",
			     "a":"is"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"Everyone __________ excited today.",
			     "a":"is"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"The internet ______ a wonderful thing.",
			     "a":"is"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"That _______ my favourite movie.",
			     "a":"is"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"Who ________ your best friend?",
			     "a":"is"}
			 ,
			 {
			     "q":"Where __________ your brothers?",
			     "a":"are"}
		     ],
		     "help":"Use 'am' with 'I'.<br>Use 'is' with 'he','she','it'<br>Use 'are' with 'we,'us','you','they'.<br>Use 'is' with singular or uncountable subjects.<br>Use 'are' with plural subjects.<br>",
		     "helpurls":["http://www.grammar.cl/Present/To_Be.htm"]
		 },
		 "2":
		 {
		     "question_prompt":"Make the sentence negative.",
		     "example":{
			 "question":"She is a student",
			 "answer":"She is not a student"
		     },
		     "questions":
		     [	 
			 {"q":"He is a doctor.",
			  "a":"He is not a doctor./He isn't a doctor./He's not a doctor."},
			 {"q":"She is happy.",
			  "a":"She is not happy./She isn't happy./She's not happy."},
			 {"q":"They are my friends.",
			  "a":"They are not my friends./They aren't my friends./They're not my friends."},
			 {"q":"It is hot today.",
			  "a":"It is not hot today./It isn't hot today./It's not hot today."},
			 {"q":"You are beautiful.",
			  "a":"You are not beautiful./You aren't beautiful./You're not beautiful."},
			 {"q":"My friends are very funny.",
			  "a":"My friends are not very funny./My friends aren't very funny."},
			 {"q":"My brother's car is blue.",
			  "a":"My brother's car is not blue./My brother's car isn't blue."},
			 {"q":"Your mother is very kind.",
			  "a":"Your mother is not very kind./Your mother isn't very kind."},
			 {"q":"The people in the room are good students.",
			  "a":"The people in the room are not good students./The people in the room aren't good students."},
			 {"q":"There are a lot of books on the shelf.",
			  "a":"There are not a lot of books on the shelf./There aren't a lot of books on the shelf."},
			 {"q":"I am a superstar.",
			  "a":"I am not a superstar./I'm not a superstar."},
			 {"q":"My friends and I are good at English.",
			  "a":"My friends and I are not good at English./My friends and I aren't good at English."},
			 {"q":"Your sister, unlike her friends, is very hard working.",
			  "a":"Your sister, unlike her friends, is not very hard working./Your sister, unlike her friends, isn't very hard working."},
			 {"q":"The boys studying French are having lunch.",
			  "a":"The boys studying French are not having lunch./The boys studying French aren't having lunch."},
			 {"q":"The water is in the glass.",
			  "a":"The water is not in the glass./The water isn't in the glass."},
			 {"q":"Simon is excited today.",
			  "a":"Simon is not excited today./Simon isn't excited today."},
			 {"q":"The internet is a wonderful thing.",
			  "a":"The internet is not a wonderful thing./The internet isn't a wonderful thing."},
			 {"q":"That is my favourite movie.",
			  "a":"That is not my favourite movie./That isn't my favourite movie."},
			 {"q":"Who is a police officer?",
			  "a":"Who is not a police officer?/Who isn't a police officer?"},
			 {"q":"What food is delicious?",
			  "a":"What food is not delicious?/What food isn't delicious?"}
		     ],
		     "help":"Add 'not' after 'am' 'is' or 'are'.",
		     "helpurls":["http://www.grammar.cl/Present/To_Be.htm"]
		 },
		 "3":
		 {
		     "question_prompt":"Make the sentence into a yes/no question.",
		     "example":
		     {"question":"She is a student.",
		      "answer":"Is she a student?"},
		     "questions":
		     [
			 {"q":"He is a doctor.",
			  "a":"Is he a doctor?"},
			 {"q":"She is happy.",
			  "a":"Is she happy?"},
			 {"q":"They are my friends.",
			  "a":"Are they my friends?/Are they your friends"},
			 {"q":"It is hot today.",
			  "a":"Is it hot today?"},
			 {"q":"You are beautiful.",
			  "a":"Are you beautiful?/Am I beautiful?"},
			 {"q":"My friends are very funny.",
			  "a":"Are my friends very funny? /Are your friends very funny?"},
			 {"q":"My brother's car is blue.",
			  "a":"Is my brother's car blue?/Is your brother's car blue?"},
			 {"q":"Your mother is very kind.",
			  "a":"Is your mother very kind?/Is my mother very kind?"},
			 {"q":"The people in the room are good students.",
			  "a":"Are the people in the room good students?"},
			 {"q":"There are a lot of books on the shelf.",
			  "a":"Are there a lot of books on the shelf?"},
			 {"q":"I am a superstar.",
			  "a":"Am I a superstar?/Are you a superstar?"},
			 {"q":"My friends and I are good at English.",
			  "a":"Are my friends and I good at English?/Are your friends and you good at English?"},
			 {"q":"Your sister is very hard working.",
			  "a":"Is your sister very hard working?/Is my sister very hard working?"},
			 {"q":"The boys are having lunch.",
			  "a":"Are the boys having lunch?"},
			 {"q":"The water is in the glass.",
			  "a":"Is the water in the glass?"},
			 {"q":"Simon is excited today.",
			  "a":"Is Simon excited today?"},
			 {"q":"The internet is a wonderful thing.",
			  "a":"Is the internet a wonderful thing?"},
			 {"q":"That is my favourite movie.",
			  "a":"Is that my favourite movie?/Is that your favourite movie?"},
			 {"q":"He is a police officer.",
			  "a":"Is he a police officer?"},
			 {"q":"That food is delicious.",
			  "a":"Is that food delicious?"}
		     ],
		     "help":"To make a yes / no question with the verb 'be', move the verb to the begining of the sentence and change the full stop to a question mark.",
		     "helpurls":["http://www.grammar.cl/Present/To_Be.htm"]
		 },
		 "4":
		 {
		     "question_prompt":"Use the correct form of 'have'.",
		     "example":
		     {"question":"She _____ a new phone.",
		      "answer":"has"},
		     "questions":
		     [
			 {"q":"I ______ two brothers.",
			  "a":"have"},
			 {"q":"He ______ a blue car.",
			  "a":"has"},
			 {"q":"Ali and Hamed _______ a class at 2pm.",
			  "a":"have"},
			 {"q":"You _____ long hair.",
			  "a":"have"},
			 {"q":"My sister _____ a lot of friends.",
			  "a":"has"},
			 {"q":"My friends ______ a lot of money.",
			  "a":"have"},
			 {"q":"Your aunt ______ a beautiful house.",
			  "a":"has"},
			 {"q":"Those dogs _______ sharp teeth.",
			  "a":"have"},
			 {"q":"Your teacher _______ a big nose.",
			  "a":"has"},
			 {"q":"I ________ an idea.",
			  "a":"have"},
			 {"q":"My phone _____ a cracked screen.",
			  "a":"has"},
			 {"q":"Julie _____ a terrible voice.",
			  "a":"has"},
			 {"q":"The students ______ headaches.",
			  "a":"have"},
			 {"q":"Laila _____ too much homework.",
			  "a":"has"},
			 {"q":"They _____ a meeting at 2pm.",
			  "a":"have"},
			 {"q":"John ____ a shower every morning.",
			  "a":"has"},
			 {"q":"My brother and I ______ eggs for breakfast.",
			  "a":"have"},
			 {"q":"Terry and Dana's house _____ a lovely garden.",
			  "a":"have"},
			 {"q":"We ______ a test next week.",
			  "a":"has"},
			 {"q":"They ______ a holiday every summer.",
			  "a":"have"}
		     ],
		     "help":"Use 'has' with 'he','she','it'<br>Use 'have' with 'I','we,'us','you','they'.<br>Use 'has' with singular or uncountable subjects.<br>Use 'have' with plural subjects.<br>",
		     "helpurls":["https://www.ego4u.com/en/cram-up/grammar/simple-present/form"]
		 },
		 "5":
		 {
		     "question_prompt":"Make the sentence negative.",
		     "example":
		     {"question":"She has a new phone.",
		      "answer":"She doesn't have a new phone."},
		     "questions":
		     [
			 {"q":"I have two brothers.",
			  "a":"I do not have two brothers./I don't have two brothers."},
			 {"q":"He has a blue car.",
			  "a":"He does not have a blue car./He doesn't have a blue car."},
			 {"q":"Ali and Hamed have a class at 2pm.",
			  "a":"Ali and Hamed do not have a class at 2pm./Ali and Hamed don't have a class at 2pm."},
			 {"q":"You have long hair.",
			  "a":"You do not have long hair./You don't have long hair."},
			 {"q":"My sister has a lot of friends.",
			  "a":"My sister does not have a lot of friends./My sister doesn't have a lot of friends."},
			 {"q":"My friends have a lot of money.",
			  "a":"My friends do not have a lot of money./My friends don't have a lot of money."},
			 {"q":"Your aunt has a beautiful house.",
			  "a":"Your aunt does not have a beautiful house./Your aunt doesn't have a beautiful house."},
			 {"q":"Those dogs have sharp teeth.",
			  "a":"Those dogs do not have sharp teeth./Those dogs don't have sharp teeth."},
			 {"q":"Your teacher has a big nose.",
			  "a":"Your teacher does not have a big nose./Your teacher doesn't have a big nose."},
			 {"q":"I have an idea.",
			  "a":"I do not have an idea./I don't have an idea."},
			 {"q":"My phone has a cracked screen.",
			  "a":"My phone does not have a cracked screen./My phone doesn't have a cracked screen."},
			 {"q":"Julie has a terrible voice.",
			  "a":"Julie does not have a terrible voice./Julie doesn't have a terrible voice."},
			 {"q":"The students have headaches.",
			  "a":"The students do not have headaches./The students don't have headaches."},
			 {"q":"Laila has too much homework.",
			  "a":"Laila does not have too much homework./Laila doesn't have too much homework."},
			 {"q":"They have a meeting at 2pm.",
			  "a":"They do not have a meeting at 2pm./They don't have a meeting at 2pm."},
			 {"q":"John has a shower every morning.",
			  "a":"John does not have a shower every morning./John doesn't have a shower every morning."},
			 {"q":"My brother and I have eggs for breakfast.",
			  "a":"My brother and I do not have eggs for breakfast./My brother and I don't have eggs for breakfast."},
			 {"q":"Terry and Dana's house has a lovely garden.",
			  "a":"Terry and Dana's house does not have a lovely garden./Terry and Dana's house doesn't have a lovely garden."},
			 {"q":"We have a test next week.",
			  "a":"We do not have a test next week./We don't have a test next week."},
			 {"q":"They have a holiday every summer.",
			  "a":"They do not have a holiday every summer./They don't have a holiday every summer."}
		     ],
		     "help":"Change 'have' to 'do not have' or change 'has' to 'does not have'.",
		     "helpurls":["https://www.ego4u.com/en/cram-up/grammar/simple-present/form"]
		 },
		 "6":
		 {
		     "question_prompt":"Make the sentence into a yes/no question.",
		     "example":
		     {"question":"She has a new phone.",
		      "answer":"Does she have a new phone?"},
		     "questions":
		     [
			 {"q":"I have two brothers.",
			  "a":"Do I have two brothers?/Do you have two brothers?"},
			 {"q":"He has a blue car.",
			  "a":"Does he have a blue car?"},
			 {"q":"Ali and Hamed have a class at 2pm.",
			  "a":"Do Ali and Hamed have a class at 2pm?"},
			 {"q":"You have long hair.",
			  "a":"Do you have long hair?/Do I have long hair?"},
			 {"q":"My sister has a lot of friends.",
			  "a":"Does my sister have a lot of friends?/Does your sister have a lot of friends?"},
			 {"q":"My friends have a lot of money.",
			  "a":"Do my friends have a lot of money?Do your friends have a lot of money?"},
			 {"q":"Your aunt has a beautiful house.",
			  "a":"Does your aunt have a beautiful house?/Does my aunt have a beautiful house?"},
			 {"q":"Those dogs have sharp teeth.",
			  "a":"Do those dogs have sharp teeth?"},
			 {"q":"Your teacher has a big nose.",
			  "a":"Does your teacher have a big nose?/Does my teacher have a big nose?"},
			 {"q":"I have an idea.",
			  "a":"Do I have an idea?/Do you have an idea?"},
			 {"q":"My phone has a cracked screen.",
			  "a":"Does my phone have a cracked screen?/Does your phone have a cracked screen?"},
			 {"q":"Julie has a terrible voice.",
			  "a":"Does Julie have a terrible voice?"},
			 {"q":"The students have headaches.",
			  "a":"Do the students have headaches?"},
			 {"q":"Laila has too much homework.",
			  "a":"Does Laila have too much homework?"},
			 {"q":"They have a meeting at 2pm.",
			  "a":"Do they have a meeting at 2pm?"},
			 {"q":"John has a shower every morning.",
			  "a":"Does John have a shower every morning?"},
			 {"q":"My brother and I have eggs for breakfast.",
			  "a":"Do my brother and I have eggs for breakfast?/Do your brother and you have eggs for breakfast?"},
			 {"q":"Terry and Dana's house has a lovely garden.",
			  "a":"Does Terry and Dana's house have a lovely garden?"},
			 {"q":"We have a test next week.",
			  "a":"Do we have a test next week?"},
			 {"q":"They have a holiday every summer.",
			  "a":"Do they have a holiday every summer?"}
		     ],
		     "help":"If the sentence uses 'have', add 'do' to the begining of the sentence.<br>If the sentence uses 'has', change 'has' to 'have' and add 'does' to the begining of the sentence.<br>Change the full stop to a question mark.<br>",
		     "helpurls":["https://www.ego4u.com/en/cram-up/grammar/simple-present/form"]
		 },
		 "7":
		 {
		     "question_prompt":"Put the words in the correct order. ",
		     "example":
		     {"question":"/ can / I / English / speak /.",
		      "answer":"I can speak English."},
		     "questions":
		     [
			 {"q":"play/can/I/guitar/.",
			  "a":"I can play guitar."},
			 {"q":"English/can/You/read/books/.",
			  "a":"You can read English books."},
			 {"q":"He/pictures/paint/beautiful/can/./",
			  "a":"He can paint beautiful pictures."},
			 {"q":"help/you/can/I/.",
			  "a":"I can help you."},
			 {"q":"We/to/go/can/tomorrow/beach/the/./",
			  "a":"We can go to the beach tomorrow."},
			 {"q":"good/take/Phones/can/photos/./",
			  "a":"Phones can take good photos."},
			 {"q":"can/funny/Steven/make/a/face/./",
			  "a":"Steven can make a funny face."},
			 {"q":"Asmahan/her/not/find/can/phone/./",
			  "a":"Asmahan can not find her phone./Asmahan cannot find her phone./Asmahan can't find her phone."},
			 {"q":"spicy/can/not/eat/Jane/food/.",
			  "a":"Jane can not eat spicy food./Jane cannot eat spicy food./Jane can't eat spicy food."},
			 {"q":"not/can/Tom/dance/.",
			  "a":"Tom can not dance./Tom cannot dance./Tom can't dance."},
			 {"q":"can/drive/not/Sheama/a/car/./",
			  "a":"Sheama can not drive a car./Sheama cannot drive a car./Sheama can't drive a car."},
			 {"q":"a/she/ride/Can/bicyle/?",
			  "a":"Can she ride a bicyle?"},
			 {"q":"they/Can/swim/?",
			  "a":"Can they swim?"},
			 {"q":"you/Could/lend/me/some/money/?",
			  "a":"Could you lend me some money?"},
			 {"q":"have/more/homework/Can/I/?",
			  "a":"Can I have more homework?"},
			 {"q":"bathroom/I/go/to/the/Could/?",
			  "a":"Could I go to the bathroom?"},
			 {"q":"the/you/turn/air/on/conditioning/Could/?",
			  "a":"Could you turn on the air conditioning?"},
			 {"q":"home/Can/go/we/?",
			  "a":"Can we go home?"},
			 {"q":"he/sing/Can/?",
			  "a":"Can he sing?"},
			 {"q":"friends/your/cook/Can/?",
			  "a":"Can your friends cook?"}
		     ],
		     "help":"Use can or could between the subject and another verb (in it's base form).<br>Use 'not' between 'can' and the verb for negatives.<br>Use 'can' or 'could' at the begining of the sentence for a question.<br>",
		     "helpurls":[
			 "http://www.englisch-hilfen.de/en/grammar/can_cannot.htm",
			 "http://learnenglish.britishcouncil.org/en/english-grammar/verbs/modal-verbs/ability-permission-requests-and-advice"
		     ]
		 }
		}
}

